hillsong.com 2012-05-05

# Policies | Hillsong Australia

**Hillsong Church Ltd** ABN 37 002 745 879 ( **the Church** ) and our related entities appreciate that privacy is very important. The Church has adopted this Privacy Policy as we recognise the right of people to keep their personal information private. This Privacy Policy covers the Church's treatment of personally identifiable information that we collect or hold. Like many other organisations, the Church must comply with the National Privacy Principles contained in the Australian Privacy Act when dealing with personal information.

### 1\. The information we collect

_All services (including various other activities) of Hillsong Church are recorded. Images of the people attending or participating in the service (or other activity) may be used and shown in our TV ministry, Resources and for other promotional purposes and commercial activities. By attending any service (or other activity) you agree to Hillsong Church using your image and personal information in these recordings._

The Church will collect general information about you, such as your name, address, contact details so the Church can contact you. We may also collect this and other types of personal information during the course of dealing with you, for example when you wish to obtain goods or services from the Church, when you register for conferences or events, and when you participate in Church activities or complete other forms. The information collected may include some sensitive information (as defined by the Privacy Act), such as health information or information about your beliefs, relevant to the services or assistance you have requested from the Church. In the interests of security and safety, and the comfort of the Church community, the Church also operates video cameras within and around some Church premises.   
Where practicable, the purpose for which we collect personal information will be made clear at the time of collection. If you do not provide us with certain information we may be unable to provide you with access to some of our services or the assistance you have requested.   
Users can generally visit the Church website without revealing who they are or other personal information unless they log on, place an order or register with us. The Church will not collect any personal information about visitors to the website except when they knowingly provide it.

### 2\. How we use your information

The Church will use the personal information we collect for the purpose disclosed at the time of collection, or otherwise as set out in this Privacy Policy. We will not use your personal information for any other purpose without first seeking your consent, unless authorised or required by law. Generally we will only use and disclose your personal information as follows:   
(a) to establish and maintain your involvement with the Church, including providing you with newsletters;   
(b) to provide the products or services you have requested from the Church;   
(c) to answer your inquiry;   
(d) to register you for events, conferences or promotions;   
(e) to assist us to make the Church's sites, services and products more valuable to our community;   
(f) for direct promotion of products or services and to keep you informed of new developments we believe may be of interest to you. If we contact you in this way without obtaining your prior consent, we will provide you with the opportunity to decline any further promotional communications;   
(g) to third parties where we have retained those third parties to assist us to operate the Church and provide the products or services you have requested, such as religious education instructors, catering and event coordinators, promotions companies, transport providers, health care providers, website hosts and IT consultants, and our professional advisers such as consultants, lawyers and accountants. In some circumstances we may need to disclose sensitive information about you to third parties as part of the services you have requested; and   
(h) to different parts of the Church to enable the development and promotion of other products and services and to improve our general ability to assist Church attendees and the wider community.

### 3\. Access to your information

You can request access to the personal information that the Church holds about you by contacting the Church's Privacy Officer as set out below. We will provide you with access to your personal information unless we are legally authorised to refuse your request. We may charge a reasonable amount for providing access.   
If you wish to change personal information that is out of date or inaccurate at any time please contact us. After notice from you, we will take reasonable steps to correct any of your information which is inaccurate, incomplete or out of date. If you wish to have your personal information deleted please let us know and we will delete that information wherever practicable.   
We may refuse your request to access, amend or delete your personal information in certain circumstances. If we do refuse your request, we will provide you with a reason for our decision and, in the case of amendment, we will note with your personal information that you have disputed its accuracy.

### 4\. Security

The Church will take reasonable steps to keep secure any personal information which we hold and to keep this information accurate and up to date. Personal information is stored in a secure server or secure files.   
The Internet is not a secure method of transmitting information. Accordingly, the Church cannot accept responsibility for the security of information you send to or receive from us over the Internet or for any unauthorised access or use of that information.

### 5\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

The Church may amend this Privacy Policy from time to time by having the amended version available at the information counters at the Church or on our website at [www.hillsong.com](http://www.hillsong.com/). We suggest that you visit our website regularly to keep up to date with any changes.

### 6\. Contacting us

If you would like any further information, or have any queries, problems or complaints relating to the Church's Privacy Policy or our information handling practices in general, please contact our Privacy Officer by filling out the form on the [enquiries page](http://myhillsong.com/contact-us), calling +61 2 8853 5353 or writing to The Privacy Officer, Hillsong Church, PO Box 1195, CASTLE HILL NSW 1765, AUSTRALIA.
